Alex Lin

Deep Learning, Data Engineer



₱ Mississauga, ON

■ alex3621lin@gmail.com

↓ +13156808371

■ The property of the prope



Summary

Talented Deep Learning Engineer with 7 years of remarkable experience

As an experienced deep learning developer, familiar with languages such as Python, and R. Have perfect solving skills using frameworks such as TensorFlow and PyTorch. Have a history of developing chatbots using natural language processing, ChatGPT, and Generative AI, and there are great examples of using them. Especially proficient in Text-To-Speech, Speech-To-Text and Computer Vision.

Professional Experience

Data Engineer, Blue | Legal

02/2022 - 06/2023

- Designed and Developed 2M pdf data-based Fast Law-Search ChatGPT using Open-Al, Elastic search, and Pine-cone vector database, and after 2 weeks, the number of users became 20,000.
- Implemented PySpark for large-scale data processing and analytics, handling datasets with 2 million records and reducing processing time by 30%.
- Utilized data mining techniques to extract valuable insights from complex datasets, including data extraction, cleaning, transformation, and analysis on datasets containing over 100 million records.
- Collaborated with data scientists to develop and implement natural language processing models using OpenAI's GPT-3, improving text classification accuracy by 3%.

NLP Engineer, Raven.ai

10/2018 - 12/2021

- Developed an NLP system that automatically classified 7.5K emails as spam or advertising mail using 3+ natural language processing methods.
- Designed Text-classification Model using low CPU, memory, and Classified 1, 250, 000 PDF files for building Search Database.
- Trained 2 Chinese-English machine translation systems that outperformed Google Translation using Transformers and some manually organizing models
- Developed the Chinese-tone learning system using AWS, TTS model, and 4TB No SQL DB.
- Improved the Processing time of the TTS model from 5s to 2s using distributed voice generation and cached memory.
- Build the OMR Program using Unet and customized Sheet-Music Parsing Technology.

Full Stack Engineer, Illumino

06/2017 - 08/2018

- Developed 8 new responsive Web Design products and 30 new features.
- Analyzed 5 modern JavaScript-based products that use company NLP and data services.
- Experimented, explored, and coded 15 new UI building blocks used to create smart, beautiful, enterprise-level software experiences.
- Translated 30+ UI/UX designs to code, resulting in visual elements of the application

Languages

English

• • • •

Chinese

Education

Dresden University of Applied Sciences,Bachelor Degree's in Computer Science ℰ

04/2015 - 03/2017 | Dersden, German

The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Advanced Diploma

09/2012 – 03/2015 Hong Kong, Hong Kong

 \bullet

Skills

Program Langauge

- C++
- Python
- Matlab
- Scalar
- R
- HTML/CSS
- Javascript

Dev Ops

- Git/Github
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Jenkins
- AWS

Web Development

- Mern Stack
- Django
- Flask

Deep learning

- Tensorflow
- Pytorch
- Keras
- Computer Vision
- Text-To-Speech/Speech-To-Text
- ChatGPT
- Generative AI
- Natural Language Processing
- Object Detection / OCR / OMR